MINZEMALULU, GABRIEL D

Dar Es Salaam | +255 784 339 933 | gabrieldee77@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

As a third-year computer engineering and IT student at the University of Dar es Salaam, my career goal is to become a software developer and data scientist with a focus on utilizing technology to solve complex problems. I bring intermediate experience in software development using frameworks Flutter and React, and intermediate-level knowledge in data science with relevant certificates in the data science fields. With analytical and problem-solving skills, ability to learn any new technology and implement within a short time, and passion for technology and innovation, I am eager and willing to apply my skills and knowledge to a position that allows me to grow as a developer and make a meaningful contribution to the team.

SKILLS

- Intermediate Level Flutter developer.
- Intermediate Level React developer.
- Intermediate level Data science Learner, having explored AI, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data visualization, Web scrapping and others.
- Basic design skills (familiarity with Canva and Figma).
- Good communication skills (fluent in English and Kiswahili).

EDUCATION

November 2020 - Present

Currently a Third Year Student, BSc. Computer Engineering and IT, University of Dar es Salaam (UDSM).

2018-2020

Advanced Level Education, St. JOSEPH'S CATHEDRAL HIGH SCHOOL, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania.

Major: PCM (Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics).

2014-2017

Ordinary Level Education, MARIAN BOYS' HIGH SCHOOL, Pwani, Tanzania.

2007-2013

Primary School, MUGINI ENGLISH MEDIUM NURSERY AND PRIMARY SCHOOL, Mwanza, Tanzania.

EXPERIENCE

HABARI NODE Plc. MWANZA

Intern, Network installation and Software Development | July 2022 to September 2022

- Worked as a Network Installation Specialist, specializing in various types of networks including wireless and fiber networks for homes and offices.
- Worked on server configurations for different network access points of the company, gaining experience in configuring servers to optimize network performance. Also conducted analysis of data usage at the company, district, and regional level, identifying trends and making recommendations for network improvements.
- Conducted network troubleshooting on various operating systems including Mac OS, Windows, and Linux, becoming proficient in network troubleshooting on multiple platforms.
- Gained valuable experience as a software developer during server configurations by learning how to operate
 on the terminal using commands, thus improving my proficiency in Linux-based operating systems and
 command-line interfaces

BUGANDO MEDICAL CENTRE (BMC).

Intern, Telecommunication and networking | July 2021 to September 2021

- Worked with LAN (Local Area Networks) around the Hospital, gaining experience with network installation for both Computers and CCTV cameras.
- Worked as Web Developer Using the Bootstrap framework, developing a Trainees website for The IT department of the Hospital.
- Worked As Database Designer Designing A database for the Trainees Website To store the details of all the trainees the department will always get.
- Worked with the design Unit in all the required designs and assigned designs.
- Worked as a computer maintenance specialist troubleshooting computers, printers, CCTV cameras, UPS
 (Uninterrupted power supply) and many other devices.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE AND LEADERSHIP

 Volunteered as A trainer for the SMART GIRLS IN ICT Program 2023, where I taught in a total 3 schools in Dar Es Salaam with a sum of more than 15 classes in total.

AWARDS AND ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS

- Participated in the Filecoin Hackathon conducted in November 2022 and finished as a runner up, with a Block chain project on Funds and Charity. Link: https://github.com/Gabriel-Dee/GiveForGood
- Participated in an AR/VR Africa Hackathon and gained an experience in the AR/VR technology.

• Certificate of Participation, Y4C Hackathon, November 2022.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Member at the Youth for Children (Y4C) Hub.
- A Member at the BUNI hub at COSTECH, as a Developer and Entrepreneur.

REFEREES

MR. EMMANUEL LUDOVICK

- HEAD TECHNICAL SUPPORT | Habari Node Plc.
- Email: ludovick.lymo@habari.co.tz
- Phone: +255 686 222 293

Ms. MILLENIUM ANTHONY

- FACILITATOR LEAD | Youth For Children (Y4C) Innovation Hub
- Email: milleniummalamla@gmail.com
- Phone: +255 743 203 524